THOMAS TARTIERE

Full-Stack & Machine Learning Engineer

904–1307 Harwood St, Vancouver, BC, V6E 1S7 (604)-349-8750 – thomas.tartiere@gmail.com



PROFILE

Entrepreneur mindset, thorough experience in fast-paced environments.

Strong analytical skills with solid understanding of machine learning and data analytics.

Strong interpersonal skills, as demonstrated through leading and collaborating in multidisciplinary teams.

Results & impact driven project manager with proven success in completing projects on time

Multilingual: Fluent in French, English & Spanish; basic Russian & German.

EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Developer

01/2017 to Now

Panevo, Vancouver

- Built a new platform to collect, visualize & analyze energy-data from large industrial corporations, from a blank page to production.
- Implemented machine learning models to improve asset management & energy performance.
- Managed all aspects of software development from roadmaps to infrastructure and customer support.

R&D Project Manager

01/2012 to 12/2016

Enertime, Paris then Vancouver

Led the development of innovative clean energy technologies

- Developed software tools for advanced modeling and optimization of complex industrial systems.
- Coordinated multidisciplinary teams in multi-million \$ research projects
- Published 8 conference & journal articles, 1 patent

EDUCATION

Online (Coursera, Udacity...)

2015 to now

Completed 10+ courses on Machine Learning & Data science

Stanford University, USA

2009-2010

M. Sc. in Mechanical Engineering

Ecole Centrale Paris, France

2008-2010

M. Sc in General Engineering

Preparatory classes in Sciences, France 2006-2008

Intensive preparation for top Engineering Schoolsh

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Programming: Python, C\C++, Javascript
- Machine Learning (scikit-learn, xgboost)
- Deep Learning (Tensor Flow, Keras)
- Full-stack web development
 - Back-End (Django, RESTful API, Redis, RabbitMQ)
 - Front-End (Vue.JS, JS tools)
 - DevOps (Microsoft Azure)
- Data cleaning and exploration
- Image processing, time-serie analysis
- Certified Project Management Professional (PMP)
- Professional written and oral communication

ACCOMPLISHMENTS / AWARDS

- Award for the Best Student Project at Ecole Centrale Paris (2010)
- Rotary Foundation Ambassadorial Scholarship (2010)
- French Academy Scholarship (2010)
- Rowing Club President, Ecole Centrale Paris (2009-2010): involved in national and international university events.
- French National Programming Competition : Finalist (2005)